Guide to the W. K. Rose Papers, 1914-1970 (bulk 1940-1968)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
W. K. Rose Papers
1914-1970
1940-1968
Rose, W. K.
10.6 cubic feet (13 boxes)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
The William K. Rose Papers document Vassar College English Professor Rose’s study of modernist literature, Vorticism, and in particular, the writings of Wyndham Lewis. The majority of the correspondence in the collection documents Rose’s efforts to locate and study Lewis’s letters to friends and associates. Files include correspondence, research and subject files, press clippings, manuscripts, notebooks, playbills, periodicals, photographs, and audio tape.
Biographical Note
William Kent Rose (1924-1968), professor of English, joined the Vassar faculty in 1953, after teaching at Stanford University, Williams College, and the University of California in Berkeley. Born William Rosenberg in Healdsburg, California, Rose, pursued Bachelor’s and Master’s degrees at Stanford University, before graduating with a doctorate from Cornell University in 1953. His doctoral dissertation on the English artist, novelist and social critic Wyndham Lewis (1882-1957), a co-founder of the Vorticist movement, was the basis of his first publication, Wyndham Lewis at Cornell (1961), which led to Rose’s published collection of Lewis’ correspondence, The Letters of Wyndham Lewis (1963).
While a faculty member at Vassar, Rose frequently traveled to England to research the works of Ezra Pound, T.S. Eliot, James Joyce, and Wyndham Lewis. At the time of his death, Rose was at work on a literary study tentatively called “The Men of 1914,” which focused on the literary revolution centered in London between 1909 and 1920. Awarded Guggenheim and Vassar Faculty Fellowships to support his research, Rose was diagnosed with a brain tumor in August of 1968, which brought a close to his research. Before his death, William K. Rose bequeathed funds to Vassar College for graduate fellowships in the arts, known as the Rose Fellowship. Rose’s partner was art historian Eugene A. Carroll, a fellow Vassar professor.
Scope and Content Note
The Papers of William K. Rose measure 10.6 cubic feet and date from 1914 - 1968, with the bulk of the material dating from 1940 - 1968. The papers document Rose’s study of modernist literature, Vorticism, the works of Ezra Pound, T.S. Eliot, James Joyce, and in particular, the writings of Wyndham Lewis, the subject of his doctoral research. The papers contain correspondence with publishers and literary figures, as Rose traveled to England frequently to research Wyndham Lewis and the literary cohorts with whom he was associated. Some files contain carbon copies of Rose’s outgoing letters. Correspondents in this series include Richard Aldington, Joseph Alsop, Agnes Bedford, Clive Bell, Quentin Bell, Saul Bellow, Elizabeth Bishop, Elizabeth Bowen, Kenneth Clark, Ivy Compton-Burnett, T.S. Eliot, Duncan Grant, Peggy Guggenheim, Granville Hicks, Robert Kennedy, Denise Levertov, Anne Wyndham Lewis, Wyndham Lewis, Dwight MacDonald, Archibald MacLeish, Marshall McLuhan, Marianne Moore, Iris Murdoch, Dorothy Pound (Mrs. Ezra Pound), Ezra Pound, Dame Edith Sitwell, Adlai Stevenson, Julian Symons, Eudora Welty, and Rebecca West. See the Papers of Eugene A. Carroll for correspondence (1960s) to and from Rose’s partner, Carroll.
Financial and Legal files hold documentation of Rose’s management of the family (Rosenberg) estate. Family correspondence from his noteworthy uncle, “Rube” Goldberg, is held in Series 1, Correspondence.
Subject files in the collection document Rose’s research efforts in his writing of The Letters of Wyndham Lewis. Notes and note cards document Rose’s research. Research notes also include documentation of Rose’s efforts at the time of his death to complete a literary study titled “The Men of 1914,” which focused on the literary revolution in London between 1909 and 1920. The series includes subject files arranged by W.K. Rose by name of literary figures, often containing periodicals from the early 1900s through the 1920s and 1960s, including the Hudson Review, James Joyce Quarterly, Paris Review, and Poetry Review. Subject files include an original prospectus announcing Sylvia Beach’s proposal for the original printing of Ulysses. The series files also include Rose’s writings as a college student and his teaching files from Vassar College. Writings include drafts of The Letters of Wyndham Lewis, poetry, essays, and article drafts about Wyndham Lewis and related topics of the period, as well as his Stanford University thesis and Cornell doctoral dissertation, published articles, and book reviews.
Printed materials include book reviews of The Letters of Wyndham Lewis, and articles and periodicals on or by Wyndham Lewis. The series also includes Rose’s collection of playbills, programs and exhibition catalogues documenting theater, music and dance performances Rose attended from his childhood years onward.
Ephemera in the collection includes an undated, framed invitation to a Blast (the Vorticist journal) dinner at Dieudonne Restaurant in the U.K. Photographs in the collection are primarily related to Rose’s literary research. See the Papers of Eugene Carroll for photographs of William K. Rose and Eugene Carroll’s friends, family, and documentation of foreign travel. Two audiotapes in the collection document interviews conducted by W.K. Rose, one with Yves Tinayre (1968), and one with Iris Murdoch (1967, see also in print form, subseries Published Works).
Access
Student materials in box 7 are restricted. Otherwise, this collection is open for research according to the
regulations of the Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library
without any additional restrictions.
Related Materials
See the Papers of Eugene Carroll for additional W.K. Rose holdings including journals, writings, realia, and Eugene Carroll’s text drafts for the W.K. Rose memorial service.
Eugene Carroll Papers
Separated Materials
(12) issues of Action, newspaper published by Oswald Mosley, British Union of Fascists, June 25, 1938 - November 12, 1938
(62) issues of The Listener, BBC October 1934 - September 1964
Subject Headings
Names:
Brown, Jane; Burkhart, Charles; Isaak, W. G.; Kahma, David; Lewis, Wyndham, 1882-1957; Aldington, Richard, 1892-1962; Alsop, Joseph, 1910-; Bedford, Agnes; Bell, Clive, 1881-1964; Bell, Quentin; Bellow, Saul; Bishop, Elizabeth, 1911-1979; Bowen, Elizabeth, 1899-1973; Burkhart, Charles; Clark, Kenneth, 1903-1983; Compton-Burnett, I. (Ivy), 1884-1969; Cunard, Nancy, 1896-1965; Eliot, T. S. (Thomas Stearns), 1888-1965; Goldberg, Rube. 1883-1970; Grant, Duncan, 1885-1978; Guggenheim, Peggy, 1898-1979; Hicks, Granville, 1901-1982; Kennedy, Robert F., 1925-1968; Levertov, Denise, 1923-; Lewis, Anne Wyndham; Lewis, Wyndham, 1882-1957; MacDonald, Dwight; MacLeish, Archibald, 1892-1982; McLuhan, Marshall, 1911-; Moore, Marianne, 1887-1972; Murdoch, Iris; Pound, Dorothy; Pound, Ezra, 1885-1972; Sitwell, Edith, Dame, 1887-1964; Stevenson, Adlai E. (Adlai Ewing), 1900-1965; Symons, Julian, 1912-; Welty, Eudora, 1909-; West, Rebecca, Dame, 1892-
Organizations:
Vassar College--Faculty; Cornell University--Libraries
Subjects:
English language--Study and teaching; Literature--Study and teaching; Women's colleges--New York (State)--Poughkeepsie; Authors; Literature publishing; Literature--Women authors; College teachers; Modernism (Literature); Vorticism
VCL Categories
Literature and Writing
Encoding Information
Encoded by Laura Streett, 2019.
Acquisition Information
The Papers of William K. Rose came as a bequest in 1970 from Professor Eugene A. Carroll, who served as executor to the Rose estate.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in nine series. Correspondence was separated by name prior to processing and remains filed alphabetically.
Series List
- Series I. Correspondence, 1944-1969; (Boxes 1, 13)
- Series II. Biographical, 1940-1953; (Box 1)
- Series III. Financial-Legal, 1952-1968; (Boxes 1, 11)
- Series IV. Subject Files, 1914-1968; (Boxes 1-3, 8, 11)
- Series V. Writings, 1942-1969; (Boxes 5-7, 11, 13)
- Series VI. Printed Materials, 1914-1968; (Boxes 8-13)
- Series VII. Ephemera, 1923-1965; (Box 10)
- Series VIII. Photographs, circa 1920-1968; (Box 10)
- Series IX. Audiotape, 1967-1968; (Box 10)
Container List
- Series I. Correspondence
  - "A" - general, 1955-1967 (1.1)
  - Ackerly, J.R., 1959; (1 letter) (1.2)
  - Aldington, Richard, 1959; (1 letter) (1.3)
  - Allen, Walter, 1957-1966; (17 letters) (1.4)
  - Ayrton, Michael, 1958; (3 letters) (1.5)
  - "B" - general, 1958-1964 (1.6)
  - Barry, Lois, 1959-1968; (2 letters) (1.7)
  - Beaufort-Palmer, Sylvia, 1959; (2 letters) (1.8)
  - Bedford, Agnes, 1959-1964; (33 letters) (1.9 - 1.10, 11.1)
  - Bell, Clive, 1959; (3 letters) (1.11)
  - Bell, Quentin, 1965; (2 letters) (1.12)
  - Bellow, Saul, 1961; (1 card) (1.13)
  - Bishop, Elizabeth, 1967; (2 letters) (1.14)
  - Bliss, Arthur, 1958; (1 letter) (1.15)
  - Bowen, Elizabeth, 1960; (3 letters) (1.16)
  - "C" - general, 1959-1969 (1.17)
  - Campbell, Mary, 1959; (2 letters) (1.18)
  - Clark, Kenneth, 1967; (1 letter) (1.19)
  - Conford, Frances, 1958-1959; (7 letters) (1.20)
  - Cunard, Nancy, 1956-1963; (35 letters) (1.21 - 1.23)
  - "D" - general, 1964-1967 (1.24)
  - Daiches, David, 1951, 1963; (2 letters) (1.25)
  - D’Arcy, Rev. M.C., 1959-1960; (3 letters) (1.26)
  - De Hoghton, Sir Anthony, 1964 (1.27)
  - Drey, O. Raymond, 1958-1962; (4 letters) (1.28)
  - "E" - general, 1947-1960 (1.29)
  - Eliot, T.S., 1958-1964; (12 letters) (1.30 - 1.31)
  - Ellmann, Richard, 1964, 1968; (2 letters) (1.32)
  - Etchells, Frederick, 1958; (1 letter) (1.33)
  - "F" - general, 1944-1967 (1.34)
  - Farrell, Kathleen, 1968; (2 letters) (1.35)
  - "G" - general, 1949-1968 (1.36)
  - Gillette, Jane Brown, 1968; (5 letters) (1.37)
  - Giovanelli, Felix, 1960; (3 letters) (1.38)
  - Goldberg, Rube, 1948-1968; (5 letters, 10 holiday cards) (1.39)
  - Guggenheim, Peggy, 1953-1968; (34 letters) (1.40 - 1.41)
  - "H" - general, 1954-1968 (1.42)
  - Hart-Davis, Rupert, 1958-1959; (3 letters) (1.43)
  - Hooper, Alison, 1959-1965; (15 cards and letters) (1.44)
  - Hutchins, Patricia, 1959, 1967; (2 notes) (1.45)
  - "I - J" - general, 1959-1965 (1.46)
  - Issack, W.G., 1966; (1 letter) (1.47)
  - John, Augustus, 1958, 1959; (2 letters) (1.48)
  - "K" - general, 1945-1968 (1.49)
  - Kahma, David, 1959-1965; (11 letters) (13.1)
  - Kennedy, Jacqueline, to Mr. Rathburne, 1963-12-04; (photocopy) (1.50)
  - Kennedy, Robert, 1965, 1967; (2 letters) (1.51)
  - Kenner, Hugh, 1961-1968; (5 letters) (1.52)
  - King, Francis, 1959; (2 letters) (1.53)
  - "L" - general, 1948-1960 (1.54)
  - Lardner, John, 1946; (1 letter) (1.55)
  - Levertov, Denise, 1963-1968; (21 letters) (1.56)
  - Lewis, Anne Wyndham, 1957-1961; (21 letters) (1.57)
  - Lewis, Wyndham, 1949-1957; (4 letters, 1 telegram) (1.58)
  - "M" - general, 1958-1968 (1.59)
  - MacDonald, Dwight, 1958-1961; (3 letters) (1.60)
  - Mairet, Philip, 1959, 1963; (2 letters) (1.61)
  - McLuhan, Marshall, 1958-1959; (3 letters) (1.62)
  - Methuen & Co. Ltd. Publishers, 1958-1968 (1.63 - 1.66)
  - Michel, Walter, 1960-1968; (13 letters) (1.67)
  - Moore, Marianne, 1965; (3 letters, 1 telegram) (1.68)
  - Morgan (Theis), Louise, 1958-1960; (4 letters) (1.69)
  - Murdoch, Iris, (4 letters), (4 letters) (1.70)
  - "N" - general, 1948-1964 (1.71)
  - New Directions Publishers, 1959-1968 (1.72 - 1.73)
  - "O" - general, 1958-1967 (1.74)
  - "P" - general, 1948-1964 (1.75)
  - Pierce, Lorne, 1960; (2 letters) (1.76)
  - Porteus, Hugh Gordon, 1959; (7 letters) (1.77)
  - Pound, Dorothy, 1961-1963; (2 letters) (1.78)
  - Pound, Ezra, 1958-1959; (2 letters) (1.79)
  - Pound, Omar, 1960-1967; (4 letters) (1.80)
  - "R" - general, 1947-1968 (1.81)
  - Read, Herbert, 1959; (3 letters) (1.82)
  - Rothenstein, John, 1958-1963; (3 letters) (1.83)
  - Rovere, Richard, 1959; (1 letter) (1.84)
  - "S" - general, 1958-1968 (1.85 - 1.86)
  - Spender, Stephen, 1948-1961; (4 letters) (1.87)
  - Symons, Julian, 1958-1968; (12 letters) (1.88)
  - "T" - general, 1963-1965 (1.89)
  - Tomlin, W.E.F., 1961-1962; (3 letters) (1.90)
  - "W" - general, 1958-1964 (1.91)
  - Wees, William C., 1965-1968; (8 letters) (1.92)
  - Welty, Eudora, 1956-1962; (6 letters) (1.93)
  - "Y" - general, 1958-1965 (1.94)
  - Unidentified correspondents, 1958-1965 (1.95)
  - Valentine’s Day cards (1.96)
- Series II. Biographical
  - Auto license, France, 1953 (1.97)
  - Certificate, Cornell University, 1953 (1.98)
  - Report cards, Stanford University, 1940-1944 (1.99)
- Series III. Financial-Legal
  - Contract, Methuen & Co. Ltd. Publishers, The Letters of Wyndham Lewis, 1959 (11.2)
  - Estate records - Rosenberg, 1952-1957 (1.100)
  - Investments, contracts, 1956-1968 (1.101)
  - Tax files, 1954-1962 (1.102 - 1.103)
- Series IV. Subject Files
  - Student Work
    - College course work - notebooks, circa 1940-1949 (1.104, 1.105, - 2.6)
    - English, coursework, 1949 (2.7)
    - Stanford University, course work, 1944-1946 (2.8 - 2.12)
    - High school notebooks, circa 1930-1949 (2.13 - 2.16)
  - Teaching files
    - English course (280, 280a) materials, circa 1953-1969 (2.17 - 2.22)
    - English course (280, 280a) materials (11.3)
    - English course (380) materials - the novel, 1966-1967 (2.23 - 2.26)
    - Feminism, press clippings, offprints, 1957 (2.27)
    - Freud & Literature, notes (2.28)
    - Lecture notes, talk on Wyndham Lewis letters (2.29)
    - Vassar Assessment Committee, essay on education & teaching, 1968 (2.30)
    - Vassar contracts, agreements, administrative correspondence, 1952-1968 (2.31)
    - Vassar, notes, memoranda, 1942-1967 (2.32)
    - Williams College, English, 1948-1950 (2.33 - 3.3)
  - Research - Wyndham Lewis
    - Betty May, Cafe Royal, circa 1960-1969 (3.4)
    - Cornell University, A Review of Wyndham Lewis, P’s Papers [held at Cornell], by WKR, 1961 (3.5)
    - Guggenheim Foundation application, 1967 (3.6)
    - Letters of Wyndham Lewis, reference files (3.7)
    - Letters of Wyndham Lewis, editorial notations (3.8, 13.2)
    - Letters of Wyndham Lewis, research notes (3.9)
    - Master’s thesis - Ring W. Lardner, notes, notecards (3.10 - 3.16)
    - Men of 1914, notes (3.17 - 3.18)
    - Notecards, notebooks, circa 1940-1949 (3.25 - 4.15)
    - Pound, Ezra, notes, circa 1950-1959 (3.19)
    - Pound, Ezra, correspondence with Wyndham Lewis, photocopies (3.20)
    - Photocopies of correspondence, from Bertrand Russell, and Ezra Pound (3.21)
    - Signed note from Wyndham Lewis, rent receipt(?), tracing of artwork (3.22)
    - Visual reference materials re: Wyndham Lewis artwork (3.23)
    - Yorke, Arabella, interview transcript, 1968 (3.24)
  - Research - literary figures, periodicals
    - Eliot, T.S., The Hudson Review, 1949 (8.1)
    - Ford, Maddox Ford, The Carleton Miscellany, 1965 (8.2)
    - Joyce, James, 1948-1965 (8.3 - 8.5)
    - Joyce, James, Sylvia Beach prospectus for Ulysses, 1921 (8.6)
    - Lawrence, D.H., circa 1950-1959 (8.7)
    - Lowry, Malcolm, Prairie Schooner, 1963 (8.8)
    - Pound, Ezra, 1914-1959 (8.9 - 8.10, 11.4)
    - Pound, Ezra, 1912-1967 (8.11 - 8.15, 11.5)
    - Proust, Marcel, Le Point - Revue Artistique et Litteraire, inscribed by Nancy Cunard, 1959 (8.16)
    - Proust, Marcel, 1955-1965 (8.17)
    - Sitwell, Edith, 1934-1960 (11.6)
    - Symbolism, Surrealism, off prints, 1915-1966 (11.7)
    - Welty, Eudora, includes Place in Fiction reprint, inscribed by Eudora Welty, 1956-1961 (8.18)
    - Yeats, W.B., centenary, Tri-Quarterly, Northwestern University, 1965 (8.19)
- Series V. Writings
  - Editorial
    - The Letters of Wyndham Lewis, raft with notes (5.1 - 5.12)
    - Wyndham Lewis correspondence, transcriptions (5.13 - 5.46)
    - The Letters of Wyndham Lewis, unbound proof (6.1 - 6.4)
    - The Letters of Wyndham Lewis, draft, notes (6.5)
  - Manuscripts
    - America Mazel Tov, Shenandoah, The Washington and Lee University Review, 1967 (6.6)
    - Eminent Domain: Yeats Among Wilde, Joyce, Pound… Oxford University Press, TS, review by WKR, 1967 (6.7)
    - Essays, English papers, 1942-1948 (6.8 - 6.16)
    - Exile’s Letters, includes Wyndham Lewis photocopies, and W.K. Rose correspondence, 1967 (6.17)
    - From Border to Border, play script (6.18)
    - The Mother (6.19)
    - Panel on the Novel, Vassar, 1962 (6.20)
    - The Novels of Wyndham Lewis, drafts (6.21 - 6.32)
    - Poetry, by WKR, Anthology of Modern Poetry, with notes, circa 1960-1969 (6.33 - 6.37)
    - Poetry and journal entries, circa 1940-1949 (6.38)
    - Pound and Lewis, The Crucial Years, 1965 (6.39)
    - Short stories by WKR, submissions to Shenandoah, 1965 (6.40 6.41)
    - Synopsis of Proust’s À la recherche du temps perdu, carbon copy mimeograph proof (13.3)
    - Untitled MS on Wyndham Lewis (7.1 - 7.5)
    - Women and Men (7.6)
    - Wyndham Lewis in His Letters, draft, 1963 (7.7)
  - Theses/Dissertations
    - A Critical Study of Ring W. Lardner, Thesis submitted to the Department of English, Stanford University, 1946 (7.8)
    - Wyndham Lewis: A Study in Dissent, Thesis presented to the Faculty of the Graduate School of Cornell University for the Degree of Doctor of Philosophy, 1953 (7.9 - 7.16)
  - Published Work
    - Bow Wow, book review, Shenandoah, The Washington and Lee University Review, 1966 (7.17)
    - Exile’s Letters, Canadian Literature, 1968 (7.18)
    - Ezra Pound & Wyndham Lewis: The Crucial Years, The Southern Review, 1968 (7.19)
    - Interview with Iris Murdoch, Shenandoah, The Washington and Lee University Review, 1968 (7.20)
    - Iris Murdoch, Informally, Harper’s Bazaar, 1969 May (11.9)
    - Iris Murdoch, Informally, London Magazine, 1968 June (7.21)
    - The Literature of Gossip, The American Scholar, 1965 (7.22)
    - The Novel: An Affirmation? Vassar Alumnae Magazine, 1962 (7.23)
    - Pound & Lewis, Agenda - Wyndham Lewis Special Issue, 1969-1970 (7.24)
    - Reviews, misc. Articles by WKR, press clippings, 1943-1951 (7.25)
    - Rotting Hill, review, Furioso, 1952 (7.26)
    - Selected Poems by Stevie Smith, The Nation, 1964 (7.27)
    - So Near and Yet So Far, Shenandoah, The Washington and Lee University Review, 1965 (7.28)
    - The Suffering Joker, Shenandoah, The Washington and Lee University Review, 1965 (7.29)
    - Vassar - A Seminar in the Contemporary Novel, Vassar Alumnae Magazine, 1955 (7.30)
    - Vassar - Contemporanea, Vassar Short Story Magazine (WKR, Advisor), 1966 (7.31)
    - Vassar - The Ideal Student, Vassar Miscellany News, 1962 May (11.10)
    - Wyndham Lewis at Cornell, A Review of the Lewis Papers, Cornell University, 1961 (7.32)
    - Wyndham Lewis in His Letters, Ramparts, 1963 May (7.33)
  - Published Work by Others
    - The Death of Merlin, Charles Burkhart (7.34 - 7.37)
    - Ezra Pound’s Kensington, Patricia Hutchins, proof with editorial notations, 1964 (7.38)
    - Hadrian and Antinous, David Kahma (7.39)
    - [RESTRICTED] Vassar student papers, circa 1960-1969 (7.40)
- Series 6. Printed Materials
  - Book Reviews
    - Letters of Wyndham Lewis, Time & Tide, 1964 April (8.20)
    - Letters of Wyndham Lewis, TIME Magazine, 1964 April (8.21)
    - Letters of Wyndham Lewis, Cornell Alumni News, 1960 April (8.22)
    - Letters of Wyndham Lewis, Punch, 1963 April (8.23)
    - Letters of Wyndham Lewis, Books and Bookmen, 1963 May (8.24)
    - Letters of Wyndham Lewis, Canadian Literature, 1963 (8.25)
    - Letters of Wyndham Lewis, Methuen Books, 1963 (8.26)
    - Methuen Books catalogue, 1962 (8.27)
  - Wyndham Lewis
    - Book jackets, Wyndham Lewis publications (11.11)
    - A Note on Michael Ayrto’s The Passion of the Vine, by Wyndham Lewis, Nine, A Magazine of Poetry and Criticism, 1950 (8.28)
    - Bibliography of Wyndham Lewis by Ruthven Todd, Twentieth Century Verse, 1938 (8.29)
    - Collected periodicals, 1911-1963 (13.4)
    - Ovid Press Prospectus, Ezra Pound, T.S. Eliot, John Rodker, Wyndham Lewis, 1919 (8.30, 11.8)
    - Collected articles re: Wyndham Lewis, 1933-1968 (8.31 - 8.32)
    - Picasso, by Wyndham Lewis, The Kenyon Review, 1940 (8.33)
    - The Rot, by Wyndham Lewis, The Sewanee Review, 1949 (8.34)
    - The Enemy, A Review of Art & Literature, Wyndham Lewis, editor, 1927, 1929 (8.35, 11.12)
    - Satire & Fiction, by Wyndham Lewis, 1930 (8.36)
    - The Tyro, Wyndham Lewis, editor, 1921 (11.13)
    - Writings/articles by Wyndham Lewis, Time & Tide, The Spectator, 1931-1935 (12.1 - 12.4)
    - Wyndham Lewis tear sheets, photocopies of artwork, portraits, 1914-1919 (12.5)
  - Playbills/Programs
    - Theater playbills, performance programs, exhibition catalogues, 1920-1965 (9.1 - 9.23, 10.1 - 10.10, 12.6, 12.7)
  - Press clippings
    - Wyndham Lewis and Letters of Wyndham Lewis press clippings, 1926-1966 (12.8 - 12.10)
    - Scrapbook, Letters of Wyndham Lewis press clippings, reviews, 1963-1964 (12.11)
- Series VII. Ephemera
  - Invitation (framed) to BLAST dinner (Voriticist journal), Dieudonne Restaurant, U.K. (10.11)
  - Maps, Chekov Museum Guide, travel documents, circa 1950-1959 (10.12)
  - Menus, invitations, 1923-1965 (10.13)
  - Postcards, lithographs (10.14)
- Series VIII. Photographs
  - Ezra Pound, and Pound related environs (10.15)
  - Unidentified portraits, postcards, circa 1930-1949 (10.16)
  - W.K. Rose, circa 1940-1969 (10.17)
  - Wyndham Lewis, circa 1920-1929 (10.18)
- Series IX. Audiotape
  - Murdoch, Iris, interview, 1967-11-23; (two 1/4" tapes) (10.19)
  - Tinayre, Yves, interview, 1968-06-12; (one 17/8"tape) (10.20)